A Guide to the William Wirt Letters, 1803-1832
Library of Virginia
- Letter, 29 September 1830, William Wirt, Baltimore, to Dabney Carr, Richmond, thanking Carr for the published letter defending Wirt's acceptance of the Cherokees' case. Wirt describes the publicity and public reaction to the case, as well as his progress on the case. Wirt sends personal and family news, 4 p., ALS. (Folder 4)
- Letter, 9 October 1830, William Wirt, Baltimore, to Dabney Carr, Richmond, thanking Carr for his support on the Cherokee case. Wirt quotes letters of support from James Madison and John Marshall, and quotes his own letter to John Ross, president of the Cherokee National Council about removal to the west. Wirt attacks Thomas Loraine McKenny, Chief, Bureau of Indian Affairs. Wirt also sends personal and family news., 4 p., ALS. (Folder 4)
- Cover, n.d., William Wirt to Dabney Carr. 1826 1827 1828 1829 1830, 1 leaf, Ms. (Folder 4)
- Letter, 23 and 24 March 1831, William Wirt, Baltimore, to Dabney Carr, Richmond, reflecting on his daughter's death adn his religious beliefs. Wirt comments on Washington politics, including William H. Crawford's presidential ambitions. Wirt's preference is Henry Clay., 8 p., ALS. (Folder 5)
- Letter, 22 May 1831, William Wirt, Baltimore, to Dabney Carr, Richmond, commenting on their friendship and mentioning a visit with James Maury. Wirt discusses the presidential election and planned conventions. Wirt informs Carr of his summer travel plans., 5 p., ALS. (Folder 5)
- Letter, 16 June 1831, William Wirt, Baltimore, to Dabney Carr, Richmond, stating that he had a court appearance on the Eastern Shore of Maryland. Wirt mentions his summer travel plans and election activities. (Folder 5)
- Letter, 15 July 1831, William Wirt, Baltimore, to Dabney Carr, Martinsburg, again mentioning his travel plans, and stating that he will not run for Congress., 1 leaf, AL., signature cut from letter. (Folder 5)
- Letter, 22 August 1831, William Wirt, Sweet Sulphur Springs, [Virginia], to Dabney Carr, Scottsville, Albemarle County, [Virginia], describing his travels to the springs and his accomodations. Wirt comments on work he needs to do and mentions the Kentucky elections., 3 p., ALS. (Folder 5)
- Letter, 30 September 1831, William Wirt, Baltimore, to Dabney Carr, Richmond, regarding his nomination as the Antimasonic presidential candidate, analyzing the political situation, and asking for news and reactions., 6 p., ALS. (Folder 5)
- Letter, 5 October 1831, William Wirt, Annapolis, to Dabney Carr, Richmond, analyzing his support and chances in the presidential election., 2 p., ALS. (Folder 5)
- Letter, 7 October 1831, William Wirt, Annapolis, to Dabney Carr, Richmond, discussing his campaign, press reaction to his candidacy, and his campaign biography. Wirt mentions Chapman Johnson, Duff Green, Thomas Jefferson, and David Watson., 7 p., ALS. (Folder 5)
- Letter, 26 October 1831, William Wirt, Baltimore, to Dabney Carr, Richmond, thanking Carr for the biographical sketch and mentioning requests for it. Wirt mentions a letter by Thomas Jefferson, "Democritus," and the presidential election., 3 p., ALS. (Folder 5)
- Letter, 2 November 1831, William Wirt, Baltimore, to Dabney Carr describing his daughter Elizabeth's marriage to Lieutenant Louis Goldsborough of the United States Navy. Wirt comments on Thomas Jefferson Randolph's permission to use letter by Thomas Jefferson. He mentions another letter by Jefferson regarding the University of Virginia. Wirt comments on the National Republican convention, the press, and Henry Clay's prospect in the election., 4 p., ALS. (Folder 5)
- Letter, 23 November 1831, William Wirt, Annapolis, to Dabney Carr, Richmond, concerning newspaper reports, subscriptions, Clay's activities, and the progress of the election., 4 p., ALS. (Folder 5)
- Letter, 27 November 1831, William Wirt, Baltimore, to Dabney Carr, discussing his motives in accepting the Antimasonic nomination. Wirt also comments on what course to take since Clay's nomination by the National Republicans., 4 p., ALS. (Folder 5)
- Letter, 5 December 1831, William Wirt, Baltimore, to Dabney Carr, Richmond, sending box of printed materials on Antimasonry and recommending rural distribution. Wirt states that the probable nomination of Clays is a relief to him. He comments on Jackson's message. Wirt has read Galt's life of Byron., 4 p., ALS. (Folder 5)
- Letter, 12 January 1831 [1832], William Wirt, Baltimore, to Dabney Carr, Richmond, stating that he is recovering from an illness and that he is seeking a way out of the Antimasons nomination. Wirt had an interview with Whittlesley about this. Wirt comments on prospects for the election., 8 p., ALS. (Folder 5)
- Cover, n.d., William Wirt to Dabney Carr 1831, 1 leaf, Ms. (Folder 5)